Guide to the Papers of Jefferson Davis documents and reference collection, 1815-2015 MS 638
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: Reference tools for accessing documents, 1815-2015
  - Subseries E: Family and Genealogy files
    - Genealogy: genealogical charts Volume 4 (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Samuel Emory Davis and ancestors (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Joseph Emory Davis and Mary Lucinda Davis Mitchell (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Florida Davis McCaleb Laughlin and Caroline Davis Robins Leonard (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Joseph E. Davis probate file, Old Courthouse Museum (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Benjamin Davis (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Samuel A. Davis (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Anna / Anne / Ann Eliza Davis Smith (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Isaac Williams Davis (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Lucinda Farrar Davis Davis Stamps (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Amanda Davis Bradford (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Matilda Davis (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Mary Ellen Davis Davis (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Jefferson Davis (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: Howell / Kempe Family (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Philadelphia records - Samuel E. Davis relatives and ancestors (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Bradford family legal records - West Feliciana Parish, LA (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Lise Mitchell journal (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Lise Mitchell journal and transcription, incomplete (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Lise Mitchell journal, typescript (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Mitchell family papers (6 folders, 1870-1918) (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Anna Farrar Goldsborough, notes and letters (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Josie Alexander collection (Josephine McCoun Alexander Endris) (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Mary Hannaford Mitchell White, diary "Interludes" (Drawer 66)
    - Genealogy: H.A. Davis; Davis family in Wales and America (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Douglas McL. More, genealogy charts (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Kirk Bentley Barb, "Genealogy of Jefferson Davis" (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: William H. Whitsitt, "Genealogy of Jefferson Davis" (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Helen Davis Brown (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Richard R. Flowers, "The Ancestors and Descendants of Jefferson Davis" (Drawer 67)
    - Life magazine and People magazine articles on Civil War notable descendants (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Davis Family Association newsletters (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Jefferson Davis Family Association coloring book by Caldeira (Drawer 67)
    - Genealogy: Jefferson Davis Family Association reunions (Drawer 67)
  - Subseries F: Image files
    Includes a copy of the image as well as source information.
    - Cartoons: Traitor's Dream (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoons: Jefferson Davis on his stand (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoons: Prize fight between Abraham Lincoln and Jefferson Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoons: Why don't you take it? (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis caricature, Harper's Weekly (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Masterly Inactivity (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The Food Question Down South (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Condition of the Mining Bureau (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis After the Fall of Fort Sumter, 1861 (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Ballandigham's Plight (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The True Peace Commissioners (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Democratic Candidates of 1862 and 1864 (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis as Unprotected Female (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Dress Wearing Jefferson Davis Flees Union Cavalry (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Carte de visite of Jefferson Davis in a dress (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis Hoops Skirts and Southern Chivalry (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: So-called President in Petticoats (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis in a cell (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Freedom's Immortal Triumph (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jeff's race for the last ditch (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Uncle Sam's Menagerie (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The Bad Bird and the Mudsill (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The Last and Best Portrait of Jefferson Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis Bathing at Fortress Monroe (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Andersonville and Fortress Monroe (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: For Sale - Warranted Sour Apple (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Time Works Wonders (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Anything for Revenge (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The Liberal Conspirators (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The Life of Jefferson Davis in Five Expressive Tableaux (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Why He Cannot Sleep (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: We Have Come to Stay (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Chicago Platform and Candidate (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Gentlemen Passed Over by the Convention (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Union and Confederate covers (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Finding the Last Ditch (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: John Brown Exhibiting his Hangman (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jeff's Last Skedaddle (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Head of the Confederacy on a New Base (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The Chase-ed Old Lady of the CSA (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Capture of Jefferson Davis at Irwinville, Georgia (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis in petticoats (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Capture of Jefferson Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: End of Jefferson Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Two Union covers (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Confederacy in petticoats (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Now Therefore I, Jefferson Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: The Last Ditch (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis in Hoop Skirt (Drawer 67)
    - Cartoon: Jefferson Davis by David Levine (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Jefferson Davis and Mrs. Davis at a reception (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis in a ballgown (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Jefferson Davis and Varina Howell Davis portrait, 1867 (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis portrait painted by Henry Byrd (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Unsourced photos of Varina Howell Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Four generations of Davis women (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Davis children in Montreal (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Jefferson Davis Jr. in uniform (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Anne Davis in London (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Anne Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Anne Davis, Daughter of the Confederacy (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Joseph E. Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Eliza B. Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis by Ruth Burgess (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Samuel Emory Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: William Stamps and Lucinda Davis Stamps (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Howell family (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Jefferson Davis, Jr. (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Assorted Davis family photos from "Jefferson Davis: The Inner Life" (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Davis family and other images from Beauvoir scrapbook (Drawer 67)
    - Family: 2 portraits, possibly Varina Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Anne Davis portrait by John P. Walker (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis, 1849 (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Samuel Emory Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Jefferson Davis, Jr., Virginia Military Institute (Drawer 67)
    - Family: William H. Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Margaret Howell Stoess (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Joseph Evan Davis, 1859-1864 (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Howell brothers - Beckett, Jefferson, and William (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis at Fort Monroe, 1866 (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis and child, 1850s (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Maunsell White photos (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Varina Howell Davis tintype, 1859-1861 (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Jefferson Davis and Varina Howell Davis (slides) (Drawer 67)
    - Family: Jefferson Davis (slides) (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis inauguration in Montgomery, Alabama (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Army at Rio Grande (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Plaza, Monterrey, Mexico (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Battle of Monterrey (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Letter of capitulation (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Battle of Buena Vista (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Various Mexican War (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Seceeding Mississippi delegation in Congress (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Confederate Presidential Ballot (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis and first Confederate Cabinet (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Various CSA generals and Confederate cabinet members (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: 97 Portraits of Confederate Generals, 1894 (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis and generals (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Pickett's Charge (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Deserted camp and wounded Zouave (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Bank of Selma $50 bill with Jefferson Davis image (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: CSA $1000 stock certificate with Jefferson Davis image (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Confederate $50 bill (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Confederate stamps (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: CSA stationery (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Sheet music cover with Jefferson Davis drawing "Confederacy March" (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis funeral, New Orleans (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Civil War railroads (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis' flight, painting, 1865 (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Black Hawk War (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis flight, April-May 1865, Frank Vizetelly sketches (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: U.S. Senate debating, 1850 (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: U.S. Senate during compromise of 1850 debate (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Reconstruction conference at Sulphur Springs 1869 (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Oscar Wilde description and sketch, 1882 (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Mary Chesnut photos (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: W. A. Jackson, Davis' coachman (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Philip Alexander Work (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: John J. Abert (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: M. C. Meigs (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Varina Howell Davis jewelry, color photos (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis snake jug (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Brierfield button (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Civil War leaders; Matthew Brady and contemporaries (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Miscellaneous (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: from Beauvoir scrapbook (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: "Freedom" by Thomas Crawford (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis project office photos and negatives, including Lynda Crist, Mary Dix, and others (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: S. W. Higginbotham (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: J. Jordon (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Major Alexander B. Bradford (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jubal Anderson Early (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Cabinet, Montgomery, Alabama (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Roger Jones, John G. Barnard, Sylvanus Thayer, Alexander McComb (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis metal token (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Interment of the remains of Jefferson Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Jefferson Davis memorial funeral procession, Raleigh, NC, 1893 (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: James H. Jones (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Landscape painting reputed to be by Jefferson Davis (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Judah P. Benjamin and DeBousignac family gravemarkers (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations: Nathan Towson (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Jefferson Davis birthplace (Fairview, KY) (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Beauvoir (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Beauvoir with nurse and baby carriage (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Lexington, KY, 1823 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: West Point paintings, lithographs, and maps, 1826-1830, 1840 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Rosemont, 1904 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Fort Armstrong (Drawer 67)
    - Images: House where Jefferson Davis married Sara Knox Taylor, 1835 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Old War Department (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Brierfield in ruins, 1950s (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Slave quarters, Jefferson Davis' Mississippi plantation (Drawer 67)
    - Images: "Images of the White House of the Confederacy" (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Confederate White House (Drawer 67)
    - Images: US Customs House / CSA Treasury, 1861-1865 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: The Capitol of Richmond, 1865 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: The Fall of Richmond, 1865 (Drawer 67)
    - Image: Raising the Stars and Stripes Over Mississippi Capitol, 1865 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: The Exact Spot Where Jefferson Davis Was Captured in 1865 (photo taken 1894) (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Where Jefferson Davis was arrested, 1865 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Jefferson Davis' first cell at Fortress Monroe, 1865 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Jefferson Davis' Memphis home, 129 E. Court St. (later 251) ca. 1875 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Jefferson Davis' Memphis home, 98 Court St. (later 210) (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Jefferson Davis site of death in New Orleans (Payne-Fenner House) ca. 1889 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Photos of Beauvoir by Wilson, ca. 1885 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: David family grave site, Hollywood Cemetery, 1903 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Stone Mountain, 1967 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Samuel A. Davis home (Oak Ridge, Warren Co., Mississippi) (Drawer 67)
    - Images: J.A. and Margaret D. Hayes home, Memphis, 1884 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Homes and vacation spots (Hayes home in Colorado Spring, CO; Hotel del Coronado in San Diego, CA; Lake Mohonk Mountain House, NY; Montgomery, AL house) (Drawer 67)
    - Images: DC residence, 238 G. St., 1857-1859 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Cabin John Bridge (Washington Aqueduct) 1853 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: St. Paul's in Richmond (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Church of the Redeemer, Biloxi, Miss. (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Hurricane Plantation (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Monterrey and Buena Vista (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Fort Winnebago, 1827 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Vicksburg Marine Hospital, ca. 1895 (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Diamond Place Plantation (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Sugar Grove, New Hope, KY (Drawer 67)
    - Images: Brierfield, 1860s (Drawer 67)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 1 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 2 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 3 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 4 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 5 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 6 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 7 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 8 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 9 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 10 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 11 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 12 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 13 (Drawer 68)
    - Illustrations and images featured in Papers of Jefferson Davis Volume 14 (Drawer 68)
  - Subseries G: Correspondence files for Papers of Jefferson Davis project, ca 1964-2015
    Correspondence regarding permission to publish and similar requests from researchers.
    - Alabama - D.C. (Drawer 69)
    - D.C. / NHPRC research correspondence (Drawer 70)
    - Florida - Kentucky (Drawer 71)
    - Louisiana - Minnesota (Drawer 72)
    - Mississippi (Beauvoir, Hurricane Katrina) (Drawer 73)
    - Mississippi (Old Courthouse Museum) - North Dakota (Drawer 74)
    - Ohio - Texas (by town names, D-F) (Drawer 75)
    - Texas (by town names, G-H) - Virginia (Drawer 76)
    - Washington state; foreign locations; Individuals A-E (Drawer 77)
    - Individuals, F-M (Drawer 78)
    - Individuals, N-Z (Drawer 79)
    - Postcards written to Papers of Jefferson Davis Project (Drawer 80)
  - Subseries H: Spreadsheet lists tracking documents / companions to Master card set (electronic)
    Spreadsheets are accessible by Woodson staff (on the departmental server) and can be shared upon request. Contact woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
    About the spreadsheets: The 5x8 slips (Jefferson Davis items) and the 3x5 slips (Varina) contain far more information about individual documents than can be displayed in these spreadsheets and are the resources most read and copied by researchers, who use them as a guide to the document files and microfilm. The newspaper print files are also very popular, as are the chronolog slips (3x5). For chronology, check the "official" set of the Davis Papers in the Woodson Research Center reference area; many additions and corrections added in the margins.
  - Subseries I: Index to Biographical Sketches published in Volumes 1-14
    The sketch index includes major family properties described in the edition. Occasionally, the published sketches are updated with later information–see marginalia in office copy of the edition. This index is useful for convenience, whether in electronic or printed format. It indicates family members, identifies people with the same or very similar names (James Brown, William Black, Albert Sidney Johnston, George W. Jones, Mary Custis Lee are examples), individuals with aliases or who changed their names, nicknames and names by which they were known, which was often the middle name. Some persons have two biographical sketches.
    - Index cards 3x5" in Jefferson Davis card catalog (Drawer JD card catalog in reading room)
  - Subseries J: Inventory lists of documents in binders by owning repository
    - Listing of microfilm reels by Jefferson Davis Project's letter-code identifier system, including brief description of contents (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - National Archives (NA) lists: microfilm reels AS-CI (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - National Archives (NA) lists: microfilm reels CJ-GW (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - National Archives (NA) lists: microfilm reels GY-IN (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - National Archives (NA) lists: microfilm reels IY-KG (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - National Archives (NA) lists: microfilm reels KH-MK (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - National Archives (NA) lists: microfilm reels PJ-XH, all of Record Group 109, Civil War period (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - National Archives (NA) lists: microfilm reels XI-XK, A, C, E (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - National Archives (NA): photocopied lists 1-76 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - National Archives (NA): photocopied lists 77-150 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - National Archives (NA): photocopied lists 151-219 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - National Archives (NA): photocopied lists 220-324 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Inventories of Jefferson Davis letters and speeches at other repositories (A-C) (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Alabama Archives, Josie Alexander Collection, Architect of the Capitol, Arizona State University, Atlanta Historical Center, Percival Beaucroft, Beauvoir, Boston Public Library, Brown University, Carnegie-Stout Public Library, Milicent Helm Chapman, Chicago Historical Society, Columbia University, Confederate Imprints
    - Inventories of Jefferson Davis letters and speeches at other repositories (D-G) (Box 37, Folder 2)
      Dallas Historical Society, Adele Hayes-Davis Davis, Richard W. Davis, Duke University, Emory University, Filson Club Historical Society, Gilder Lehrman Collection
    - Inventories of Jefferson Davis letters and speeches at other repositories (H-L) (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Harvard University, Bert Hayes-Davis, Historic New Orleans Collection, Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Huntington Library, Illinois State Historical Society, Iowa Archives, Jefferson Davis Project, Library of Virginia, Louisiana State Museum, Lousiana State University
    - Inventories of Jefferson Davis letters and speeches at other repositories (M-O) (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Maryland Historical Society, Miami University, Mississippi State University, Pierpoint Morgan Library, Morristown National Historical Park, New York Public Library, Norton Art Gallery, Old Court House Museum
    - Inventories of Jefferson Davis letters and speeches at other repositories (R-Univ AL) (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Rice University, Rosenbach Foundation, Smithsonian, South Carolina Archives, Hudson Strode, Tennessee Archives, Transylvania University, U.S. Army (Carlisle Barracks), U.S. Military Academy, University of Alabama
    - Inventories of Jefferson Davis letters and speeches at other repositories (Univ Calif - Univ Va) (Box 37, Folder 6)
      University of California, University of Georgia, University of Memphis, University of Michigan, University of North Carolina, University of South Carolina, University of Texas, University of Virginia
    - Inventories of Jefferson Davis letters and speeches at other repositories (V-Y) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Virginia Historical Society, Warren County Courthouse, Joel and Barbara Webb, Western Reserve Historical Society, William and Mary, Woodville Republican newspaper archives, Yale University
    - Inventory of documents from the Museum of the Confederacy (ViRC) (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
    - Inventory of documents from Tulane University (LNT) (Box 37, Folder 10-11)
    - Inventory of documents from Library of Congress (DLC) (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Inventory of documents from Library of Congress H.B. Fants checklists (Box 37, Folder 13-14)
    - Inventory of documents from the Mississippi Dept. of Archives and History (Ms-Ar) (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
    - Inventory of documents from the Old Court House Museum (MsVo) (Box 38, Folder 3-6)
  - Subseries K: Publications frequently referenced during Papers of Jefferson Davis project
    Also includes pamphlets describing National Archives record groups.
    - Bench and Bar of Mississippi, by Lynch (Box 38, Folder 7-8)
    - Encyclopedia of Mississippi History (4 volumes) (Box 38, Folder 9-15, Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Publications of the Mississippi Historical Society (Volume X) (Box 39, Folder -)
    - Published archival finding aids from other repositories (Box 39, Folder -)
- Series III: Newspapers (originals) and general images, 1861-1894
  - Battle at Great Bethel, June 10, 1861. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper. (Drawer 117, Item 1)
  - Pictorial History of the War of 1861. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, vol. XII, no. 293. New York, June 29, 1861. (Drawer 117, Item 2)
  - U.S. Frigate St. Lawrence sinking the Rebel Privateer Petrel, off Charleston Harbor, on Sunday, Aug. 4, 1861. New York Illustrated News. (Drawer 117, Item 3)
  - The Great Union Gun, intended to be mounted on the deck of the Minnesota...Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, p. 196. Aug. 10, 1861. (Drawer 117, Item 4)
  - Reception by the people of New York of the Sixty-ninth Regiment. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, p. 205. Aug. 10, 1861. (Drawer 117, Item 5)
  - The War on the Mississippi-landing of Capt. Bailey and Lieut. Perkins on the levee, New Orleans...Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, p. 120. May 31, 1862. (Drawer 117, Item 6)
  - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, vol. XIV, no. 364. New York, Sept. 20, 1862. (Drawer 117, Item 7)
  - Pass of Rio Frio, on the road from Vera Cruz to the city of Mexico. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, p. 406. Sept. 20, 1862. (Drawer 117, Item 8)
  - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, vol XVII, no. 439. New York, Feb. 27, 1864. (Drawer 117, Item 9)
  - General Sherman's Rear-guard. Harper's Weekly. April 2, 1864. (Drawer 117, Item 10)